So here we are and it's race day.
This is the first day of your big race.
You've waited for this, you've trained and now you are here.
What do you do when that alarm goes off.
The first thing you need to think about before you go into any race is your nutrition.
It is very very important to eat and drink before your race.
Not 15 minutes before your race but typically 2 to 3 hours before your race, you want to have something that has some substance, some complex carbs.
The best oatmeal, bananas, any kind of hot cereal, things that are going to stay in and give you the energy you need for the long race.
The other important thing on race day is hydration.
Don't go into your race dehydrated.
It is important to wake up and have some water or sports drink so that you go into your race properly hydrated because I guarantee you after your race, you might be dehydrated.
So it is good to start out head of the game and hopefully if you fuel properly, you will end your race hydrated and excited from your big win.